# AJAY KUMAR VERMA

ajayvermaakv4@gmail.com | 9721956156 | linkedin.com/in/ajay-kumar-verma-077aab160/ | github.com/AjayKumarVerma4

#### **SUMMARY**

I have 4 year 8 months of experience in Software Industry as a Java Developer. I have significant expertise in project and account management as well as in developing, documenting, coding, modifying, testing, and implementing business technology solutions.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Software Engineer, CGI

Nov 2021 - till now

- Experience in all the phases of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) such as analyzing, designing, coding, debugging, documenting, testing and implementing business technology solutions.
- Worked on multiple releases with full featured functionality and completed it at proper time.
- Developed multiple REST APIs in Java using Spring Boot Framework and implemented microservices features with it.
- Developed multiple UI screen in application using React TypeScript.
- Resolved many bugs in different project related to OP.
- Responsible for monitoring production logs using tools like Splunk, AWS cloud watch, Dynatrace etc.
- Involved in AM Activities and done work in DevOps mode.
- Involved in build & deploy the applications on AWS.
- Involved in multiple deployments over the period by learning complex processes and end to end technology requirements.

# **Software Engineer, HCL Technologies**

Jan 2021 - Oct 2021

- Completed 14 weeks HCL FSD (Full Stack Development) training program. This training is organized by Great Learning.
- In this training I successfully completed the following courses: Foundations of Java Programming and Core Java, Frontend Engineering, Databases, Design and Architecture, Web Frameworks, DevOps, Microservices and Unit Testing, Angular.
- Completed "Online Food Delivery Application" using Angular, Spring Boot & MySQL.

#### Software Engineer, Freakcoders LLP

Jul 2019 - Dec 2020

- Developed REST APIs in JAVA using Spring Boot & Hibernate Framework.
- Developed APIs responsible for bulk actions such as bulk create, update, delete and list.
- Build databases and table structures Following MVC (Model View Controller)
- Developed HQL (Hibernate Query Language) query for sorting, searching and filtering the data.
- Architecture methodology for Web Applications.
- Designed UI using ReactJS and Angular Framework.
- Full stack developer, hands on experience in web development too.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### OP, Nov 2022 to Present

- OP is a Finland leading bank of corporates and institutions. It provide financial service, payment service, management Of cash flows etc.
- Technology Used: Java, Java 8 new Feature, Spring, Spring Boot, Docker, React, AWS etc.

#### DWP (Digital Wealth Portfolio), Nov 2021 to Oct 2022

- Technology Used: Java, Java 8 new Feature, Spring, Spring Boot.
- DWP (Digital Wealth Portfolio) an application which deals with the Investment solutions.
- In this project I developed multiple services and helped in multiple bugs for various team.
- Shared knowledge to team members on Spring boot and dwp-domain-api's.

### Indiadream, Oct 2019 to Apr 2020

- Technology Used: Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, MYSQL, Reactis.
- This project is an E-Commercial project, developed for India leading online supplier of construction material and industrial service.
- This Project is developed with the help of Java 1.8, Spring Boot 2.0.3, Hibernate 5.3.7, MySQL 5.7.32 and ReactJS.
- · In that project my role is to developed REST APIs in JAVA using Spring Boot & Hibernate Framework which perform bulk actions such as bulk create, retrive, update, delete and list.
- Build databases and table structures Following MVC (Model View Controller).
- Developed HQL (Hibernate Query Language) query for sorting, searching and filtering the data.
- Architecture methodology for Web Applications.
- Designed UI using Reactjs and UI for admin using react-admin (A frontend Framework for building admin applications).

## Viteminds, May 2020 to Dec 2020

- Technology Used: Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, MYSQL, Angular.
- This project is developed for online education, where student can join the online class, submit assignment, download materials, discuss their problems and attend the exam assigned by the trainer.
- This Project is developed with the help of Java 1.8, Spring Boot 2.0.3, Hibernate 5.3.7, MySQL 5.7.32 and Angular.
- Developed REST APIs in JAVA using Spring Boot & Hibernate Framework which perform bulk actions such as bulk create, retrive, update, delete and list. Builds database and table structures Following MVC(Model View Controller).
- Developed HQL (Hibernate Query Language) query for sorting, searching and filtering the data.
- Architecture methodology for Web Applications.
- · Designed UI using Angular.

#### **EDUCATIONS**

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science and Engineering Aug 2015 - Jun 2019 Rajkiya Engineering College Sonbhadra GPA: 7.1

Intermediate(10+2), Jul 2011 – Mar 2013 Jawahar Navodaya Vidyalaya, Basti

GPA: 6.8

High School, Apr 2009 – Mar 2011 Jawahar Navodaya Vidyalaya, Basti GPA: 8.8

**SKILLS** 

- Knowledge Of: Java, Java 8 new Features, Spring, Spring Boot, Microservices, React, MySQL, AWS, Splunk etc.
- IDE: Eclipse, STS.
- Text Editor: Visual Studio Code.

## TRAINING / WORKSHOP

- Attended Certification Workshop at IIT Kharagpur on Web Technologies, Jan 2018.
- 45 days Summar training in Java from Technex IIT BHU and certified by them.
- Completed Java Masterclass Course at KaliberMind Academy, BANGALORE.

# EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ajay-kumar-verma-077aab160/ I am an active member of HackerRank ( https://www.hackerrank.com/ajayvermaakv4).
- Management Head of SFAC (Student Fine Art Club) Council in College.
- Member of Stage Handling Committee, REC Sonbhadras Annual Fest UDBHAV18.